In this video I am going to define what is
probably the most common type of machine
本视频中，我将定义机器学习问题的最普通类型大概是什么，
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
learning problem, which is supervised
learning. I'll define supervised learning
哪些是监督学习。随后，我将给出监督学习的更正式的定义，
more formally later, but it's probably
best to explain or start with an example
但是最好还是从例子开始解释。
of what it is and we'll do the formal
definition later. Let's say you want to
假设你想要预测房屋价格。
predict housing prices. A while back, a
student collected data sets from the
不久前，一个学生从波特兰俄勒冈研究所收集数据。
Institute of Portland Oregon. And let's
say you plot a data set and it looks like
假设你绘制了一个数据集，就像这样。
this. Here on the horizontal axis, the
size of different houses in square feet,
水平轴上，不同房屋的尺寸是平方英尺
and on the vertical axis, the price of
different houses in thousands of dollars.
垂直轴上，是不同房子的价格，千万美元。
So. Given this data, let's say you have a
friend who owns a house that is, say 750
给定数据，假设有一个朋友有一栋房子，750平方英尺，
square feet and hoping to sell the house
and they want to know how much they can
想要卖掉这个房子，他们想知道能卖多少钱。
get for the house. So how can the learning
algorithm help you? One thing a learning
那么，学习算法能帮你什么呢？
algorithm might be able to do is put a
straight line through the data or to fit a
学习算法可做的一件事可能是根据数据画一条直线或者说
straight line to the data and, based on
that, it looks like maybe the house can be
用一条直线拟合数据。基于此，看上去房子可以卖大约150000美元。
sold for maybe about $150,000. But maybe this
isn't the only learning algorithm you can
但是，可能这不是你能使用的唯一的学习算法。
use. There might be a better one. For
example, instead of sending a straight
可能有一个更好的。例如，不是用一条直线拟合数据，
line to the data, we might decide that
it's better to fit a quadratic
可能觉得用一个二次函数或二阶多项式来拟合数据更好。
function or a second-order polynomial to
this data. And if you do that, and make a
假设这么做，
prediction here, then it looks like, well,
maybe we can sell the house for closer to
在这儿做一个预测，然后看上去我们可以以接近200000美元的价格卖掉这个房子。
$200,000. One of the things we'll talk
about later is how to choose and how to
后面我们要讨论的一件事就是如何选择，如何
decide do you want to fit a straight line
to the data or do you want to fit the
决定你是用直线拟合数据还是用二次函数拟合数据。
quadratic function to the data and there's
no fair picking whichever one gives your
当然，无论取哪个模型给你的朋友卖房子都是不公平的。
friend the better house to sell. But each
of these would be a fine example of a
但这是一个学习算法的很好的例子。
learning algorithm. So this is an example
of a supervised learning algorithm. And
这也是监督学习算法的例子。
the term supervised learning refers to the
fact that we gave the algorithm a data set
监督学习是指我们给算法一个数据集，并且给定正确答案。
in which the "right answers" were
given. That is, we gave it a data set of
也就是说，我们给定一个房屋数据集，
houses in which for every example in this
data set, we told it what is the right
在这个数据集中的每个例子，我们都给出正确的价格，
price so what is the actual price that,
that house sold for and the toss of the
也即这个房子卖出的实际价格，
algorithm was to just produce more of
these right answers such as for this new
算法的目的就是给出更多的正确答案，例如对待售房子，
house, you know, that your friend may be
trying to sell. To define with a bit more
比如你朋友想要卖的房子给出估价。
terminology this is also called a
regression problem and by regression
用更专业的术语来定义，它也称为回归问题，
problem I mean we're trying to predict a
continuous value output. Namely the price.
之所以称之为回归问题，我的意思就是预测连续的输出值，也就是价格。
So technically I guess prices can be
rounded off to the nearest cent. So maybe
技术上而言，假设价格被圆整到分。
prices are actually discrete values, but
usually we think of the price of a house
因此，价格实际上是一个离散值，但通常我们认为房子的价格是一个实数，
as a real number, as a scalar value, as
a continuous value number and the term
作为一个标量，作为一个连续值，
regression refers to the fact that we're
trying to predict the sort of continuous
回归指我们设法预测连续值的属性。
values attribute. Here's another
supervised learning example, some friends
这里是另一个监督学习的例子，我和一些朋友
and I were actually working on this
earlier. Let's see you want to look at
早些时候做过这个问题。假设你想要看医疗记录，
medical records and try to predict of a
breast cancer as malignant or benign. If
并且想设法预测乳腺癌是恶性的还是良性的。
someone discovers a breast tumor, a lump
in their breast, a malignant tumor is a
假设某人发现了一个乳腺瘤，在乳腺上有个肿块，一个恶性瘤就是
tumor that is harmful and dangerous and a
benign tumor is a tumor that is harmless.
它是有害的且危险的；良性瘤就是它是无害的。
So obviously people care a lot about this.
Let's see a collected data set and suppose
显然，人们很关心这个。我们来看收集到的数据集，
in your data set you have on your
horizontal axis the size of the tumor and
假设，在你的数据集中，水平轴是瘤的尺寸，
on the vertical axis I'm going to plot one
or zero, yes or no, whether or not these are
垂直轴，可以是1或0，也可以是Y或N。
examples of tumors we've seen before are
malignant–which is one–or zero if not malignant
设已经看到的肿瘤例子是恶性的对应1，良性的对应0。
or benign. So let's say our data set looks
like this where we saw a tumor of this
那么，你的数据集就像这样，我们看到这些尺寸的瘤是良性的，
size that turned out to be benign. One of
this size, one of this size. And so on.
这个尺寸，这个尺寸，等等。
And sadly we also saw a few malignant
tumors, one of that size, one of that
很遗憾，我们也看到了一些恶性的瘤，这个尺寸，这个尺寸，
size, one of that size... So on. So this
example... I have five examples of benign
这个尺寸，等等。因此，这个例子，这里我给出了五个良性肿瘤的例子，
tumors shown down here, and five examples
of malignant tumors shown with a vertical
五个恶性肿瘤的例子，恶性瘤对应垂直轴上的1.
axis value of one. And let's say we have
a friend who tragically has a breast
假设我们有个朋友，很不幸，有乳腺癌，
tumor, and let's say her breast tumor size
is maybe somewhere around this value. The
假设她的乳腺瘤的尺寸可能是这个值附近。
machine learning question is, can you
estimate what is the probability, what is
机器学习问题就是，你能否估计出瘤是良性的还是恶性的概率。
the chance that a tumor is malignant
versus benign? To introduce a bit more
引入一个更专业的术语，
terminology this is an example of a
classification problem. The term
这就是一个分类问题。
classification refers to the fact that
here we're trying to predict a discrete
分类是指我们设法预测一个离散的输出值，
value output: zero or one, malignant or
benign. And it turns out that in
0或1，恶性或良性。
classification problems sometimes you can
have more than two values for the two
在分类问题中，对于输出，你也可以多于两个值。
possible values for the output. As a
concrete example maybe there are three
在实际例子中就是，可能有三种类型的乳腺癌，
types of breast cancers and so you may try
to predict the discrete value of zero,
因此，你可能要设法预测离散值0，
one, two, or three with zero being benign.
Benign tumor, so no cancer. And one may
1,2或3，其中0是良性的。良性瘤就是说没有癌症。
mean, type one cancer, like, you have
three types of cancer, whatever type one
1就是指第一种癌症，
means. And two may mean a second type of
cancer, a three may mean a third type of
2就是指第二种癌症，3就是指第三种癌症。
cancer. But this would also be a
classification problem, because this other
这也是一个分类问题，因为这些离散的输出值，
discrete value set of output corresponding
to, you know, no cancer, or cancer type
对应于你知道没有癌症，或者癌症一、
one, or cancer type two, or cancer type
three. In classification problems there is
癌症二、或癌症三。在分类问题中，
another way to plot this data. Let me show
you what I mean. Let me use a slightly
有另一种方法来绘制这些数据。
different set of symbols to plot this
data. So if tumor size is going to be the
我们用有点不同的符号集来绘制这组数据。假设瘤的尺寸是我用来
attribute that I'm going to use to predict
malignancy or benignness, I can also draw
预测恶性或良性的特征。
my data like this. I'm going to use
different symbols to denote my benign and
我也可以这样画我的数据。我将用不同的符号来表示我的良性或恶性，
malignant, or my negative and positive
examples. So instead of drawing crosses,
或者说我的反例和正例。因此，不是画叉，
I'm now going to draw O's for the benign
tumors. Like so. And I'm going to keep
这里我将用O来表示良性瘤，就像这样。
using X's to denote my malignant tumors.
Okay? I hope this is beginning to make
我还是继续用叉表示恶性瘤。我希望这是可理解的。
sense. All I did was I took, you know,
these, my data set on top and I just
我所做的就是我将我的数据集映射到这些实线。
mapped it down. To this real line like so.
And started to use different symbols,
并且，使用不同的符号，
circles and crosses, to denote malignant
versus benign examples. Now, in this
圆圈和叉，表示恶性和良性例子。
example we use only one feature or one
attribute, mainly, the tumor size in order
在这个例子中，我们只使用了一个特征或者说一个属性，瘤的尺寸，
to predict whether the tumor is malignant
or benign. In other machine learning
来预测瘤是恶性的还是良性的。在其它的机器学习问题中，
problems when we have more than one
feature, more than one attribute. Here's
我们会有多个特征，多个属性。
an example. Let's say that instead of just
knowing the tumor size, we know both the
这儿有个例子。假设，不仅只指定瘤的尺寸，我们还知道病人的年纪。
age of the patients and the tumor size. In
that case maybe your data set will look
在这种情况下，你的数据集就是这样的，
like this where I may have a set of patients
with those ages and that tumor size and
我可能有一组病人是这些年龄的，瘤的尺寸是这样的。
they look like this. And a different set
of patients, they look a little different,
另一组病人，他们看上去有点不同，
whose tumors turn out to be malignant, as
denoted by the crosses. So, let's say you
他们的瘤是恶性的，用叉表示。
have a friend who tragically has a
tumor. And maybe, their tumor size and age
假设你有一个朋友，很不幸有一个瘤。可能，他的瘤的尺寸和她的年记在这儿。
falls around there. So given a data set
like this, what the learning algorithm
因此，给定如此的数据集，学习算法能做的
might do is throw the straight line
through the data to try to separate out
可能就是在数据上给出这样一条直线，设法将恶性瘤和良性瘤分开。
the malignant tumors from the benign one s
and, so the learning algorithm may decide
从而，学习算法可能决定
to throw the straight line like that to
separate out the two classes of tumors.
用这样的直线来分离这两类瘤。
And. You know, with this, hopefully you
can decide that your friend's tumor is
有了这个，很幸运地，你就可以决定你朋友的瘤很有可能是什么样的，
more likely to if it's over there,
that hopefully your learning algorithm
假设它在这儿，你的学习算法将会说
will say that your friend's tumor falls on
this benign side and is therefore more
你朋友的瘤位于良性区域，因此，是良性的可能性比恶性的大。
likely to be benign than malignant. In
this example we had two features, namely,
在这个例子中，我们有两种特征，
the age of the patient and the size of the
tumor. In other machine learning problems
病人的年级和瘤的尺寸。在其它的机器学习算法中，可能会有更多的特征。
we will often have more features, and my
friends that work on this problem, they
我的朋友做了这样的问题，
actually use other features like these,
which is clump thickness, the clump thickness of
他们实际上使用了其它的特征，如肿块的厚度，
the breast tumor. Uniformity of cell size
of the tumor. Uniformity of cell shape of
还有瘤细胞的尺寸的均匀性，瘤细胞形状的均匀性等，
the tumor, and so on, and other features
as well. And it turns out one of the interes-,
以及其它的特征。一个有趣的，
most interesting learning algorithms that
we'll see in this class is a learning
或更有趣的学习算法是，我们会看到，
algorithm that can deal with, not just two
or three or five features, but an infinite
一个学习算法可处理，不仅仅两到三个或五个特征，而是无穷多的特征。
number of features. On this slide, I've
listed a total of five different features.
在这个幻灯片中，我列出了总共五种不同的特征。
Right, two on the axes and three more up here.
But it turns out that for some learning
两个在轴上，三个在这儿。但是，这说明对某些学习问题，
problems, what you really want is not to
use, like, three or five features. But
你真正想要的不是使用像三个还是五个特征，
instead, you want to use an infinite
number of features, an infinite number of
而是，你想使用一个无穷多数量的特征集，一个无穷多数量的属性集。
attributes, so that your learning
algorithm has lots of attributes or
因此，你的学习算法有很多的属性或特征或线索来做预测。
features or cues with which to make those
predictions. So how do you deal with an
因此，你如何来处理这些特征呢。
infinite number of features. How do you even
store an infinite number of
你如何处理无穷多数量的特征，如何在计算机中存储无穷多数量的事物，
things on the computer when your
computer is gonna run out of memory. It
这时，你的计算机可能会溢出。
turns out that when we talk about an
algorithm called the Support Vector
以支持向量机算法为例，
Machine, there will be a neat mathematical
trick that will allow a computer to deal
就有一个灵巧的数学技巧，它允许计算机处理无穷多的特征。
with an infinite number of features. Imagine
that I didn't just write down two features
假设我没有在这儿写下两个特征，
here and three features on the right. But, imagine that
I wrote down an infinitely long list, I
也没有在这写三个特征。 假设我写下无穷长的列表，
just kept writing more and more and more
features. Like an infinitely long list of
我不停地写更多更多的特征，无限长的特征列表。
features. Turns out, we'll be able to come
up with an algorithm that can deal with
结果是，我们能提出一个算法来处理它。
that. So, just to recap. In this
class we'll talk about supervised
概括一下，在这节课上，我们仅讨论监督学习。
learning. And the idea is that, in
supervised learning, in every example in
思想是，在监督学习中，数据集中的每个例子，
our data set, we are told what is the
"correct answer" that we would have
算法将预测得到例子的“正确答案”。
quite liked the algorithms have predicted
on that example. Such as the price of the
像房子的价格，
house, or whether a tumor is malignant or
benign. We also talked about the
或瘤是恶性的还是良性的。
regression problem. And by regression,
that means that our goal is to predict a
我们也讨论了回归问题。回归是指我们的目标是预测一个连续的输出值。
continuous valued output. And we talked
about the classification problem, where
我们讨论了分类问题，
the goal is to predict a discrete value
output. Just a quick wrap up question:
目的是预测离散的输出值。
Suppose you're running a company and you
want to develop learning algorithms to
假设你运作一个公司，并且你想开发学习算法来处理两个问题中的一个。
address each of two problems. In the first
problem, you have a large inventory of
第一个问题，你有一个相同项目的清单。
identical items. So imagine that you have
thousands of copies of some identical
假设你有某些相同项目的成千上万的副本要卖，
items to sell and you want to predict how
many of these items you sell within the
你想预测下在接下来的三个月内你会卖出这些项目中的多少个。
next three months. In the second problem,
problem two, you'd like--  you have lots of
第二个问题是，你有很多用户，
users and you want to write software to
examine each individual of your
你想要写一个软件来检查每一个客户的账户，
customer's accounts, so each one of your
customer's accounts; and for each account,
你客户账户的每个账户，
decide whether or not the account has been
hacked or compromised. So, for each of
并且决定这个账户被入侵还是被破坏了。
these problems, should they be treated as
a classification problem, or as a
对每一个这种问题，应该被认为是分类问题还是回归问题？
regression problem? When the video pauses,
please use your mouse to select whichever
当视频暂停时，用你的鼠标选择四个选项中的正确答案。
of these four options on the left you
think is the correct answer. So hopefully,
you got that this is the answer. For
problem one, I would treat this as a
很高兴，你选择了正确答案。问题以，我会把它处理为回归问题，
regression problem, because if I have, you
know, thousands of items, well, I would
因为，假设我有成千上万的项目，我很可能将它看成一个实数，
probably just treat this as a real value,
as a continuous value. And
即一个连续的值。
treat, therefore, the number of items I sell,
as a continuous value. And for the
即把我要卖的项目数量看成一个连续的值。
second problem, I would treat that as a
classification problem, because I might
第二个问题，我将看成一个分类问题，
say, set the value I want to predict with
zero, to denote the account has not been
因为，我可能会设置我要预测的值为0，表示账户没有没入侵；
hacked. And set the value one to denote an
account that has been hacked into. So just
设置值为1，表示账户已经被入侵。
like, you know, breast cancer, is,
zero is benign, one is malignant. So I
因此，正如你知道的，乳腺癌是0的就是良性，1就是恶性。
might set this be zero or one depending on
whether it's been hacked, and have an
因此，我可能会设置它为0或1，看它是否被入侵。
algorithm try to predict each one of these
two discrete values. And because there's a
并用一个算法来预测这两个离散值中的一个。
small number of discrete values, I would
therefore treat it as a classification
因为，只有少量的离散值，因此，我把它作为一个分类问题。
problem. So, that's it for supervised
learning and in the next video I'll talk
这就是监督学习。下个视频中，我们将讨论非监督学习，
about unsupervised learning, which is the
other major category of learning algorithms.
它是学习问题的另一大类。